Imagine your program is like a bread factory,
你的程序好比一个面包工厂
and your function is a specific machine in your factory that makes sourdough bread.
程序中的每个函数就像工厂里生产面包的一台机器
The inputs to your function are like the ingredients,
函数的输入就像是原料
and every time you run it,
每次运行机器后
it gives you the perfect loaf.
它就会产出一条完美的面包
If you were just making some bread in your kitchen,
如果你只是在厨房里做面包
you could cut off the corners as long as you follow the general recipe.
你可以忽略一些细节 只用遵循大致的制作流程
But since your factory needs to mass-produce bread at a large scale,
但因为你的工厂需要大规模批量生产面包
you need to be a bit more careful.
你就需要更加仔细了
Your bread maker needs to be designed,
你的面包制造机器需要精心设计
so you can build several copies of it,
你可以制造许多相同的机器
and these copies can all run smoothly across the factory.
然后这些机器能在工厂按照预期来运行
One thing you'll need to avoid when designing
在设计面包机器时
your breadmaker is unintended side effects.
你需要考虑很多因素
After each loaf, your machine needs to leave
比如 每造一个面包 这个面包机都要离开工厂
the factory exactly the same as before it ran.
这样才能保证工厂的状态与造这个面包之前是完全一致的
If you don't, each machine could start interfering with the others.
如果不这样的话 就可能会发生一些意料之外的事情
For example, if running a single breadmaker
例如 如果运行单个面包机
made the entire factory one degree warmer,
会使整个工厂温度升高一度
then running several of these machines all at once
那么一次运行多台机器
would start to heat up the room.
就会让房间变热很多
This would mess up the baking temperature for
这就破坏了所有机器的烘烤温度
all the machines and you'd end up with a lot of bad bread.
这样你最终获得的面包就都不合格了
In distributed systems, your functions shouldn't
在分布式系统中的函数不应该
have side effects on variables outside their scope,
对其范围之外的变量造成影响
since this could interfere with other functions running on your cluster.
因为这可能会干扰群集上运行的其他函数
Another potential issue is contamination of your original ingredients,
另一个可能的问题是对原材料的污染
if you've ever made sourdough bread,
要做面包
you know that you need a combination of water,
你会需要水
sugar, and yeast known as the starter.
糖和酵母的组合 称为配方
Some sourdough bread factories have maintained their starters for decades,
一些面包工厂的配方在几十年里都维持原样
and they protect them the same way tech companies protect their valuable data.
他们对自己的配方保密之严格堪比科技公司对数据的保护
Your bread making machine needs to get the ingredients without
机器在使用原料制作面包时
ruining them since other breadmakers will also need them.
不能破坏原料 因为其他面包机也要使用
Bread companies do this by using a mother dough
面包公司会使用老面来达到这个目的
that can make copies of the starter,
老面可以复制多分原始配料
and these companies are very careful with this parent dough.
而工厂对这种老面的保护也十分小心
In distributed systems, you also need to be careful
在分布式系统中，你也要十分谨慎地设计函数
Whenever your functions run on some input data,
每当函数运行某些输入数据时
it can alter it in the process.
函数在整个运行过程都有可能会改变数据
If your bread-making machine protects
如果你的面包机不会破坏原料
the input ingredients and doesn't cause any side effects,
而且也不会对工厂环境造成任何额外影响
then you have a smooth and clean operation.
那么面包生产的过程将会变的非常顺畅
Similarly, if you write functions that preserve
同样 如果你编写的函数
their inputs and avoid side effects,
不会篡改原始输入数据也不会对函数范围外的变量造成影响
these are called peer functions,
这种函数被叫做纯函数
and your spark code will work well at the scale of big data.
Spark 的代码在运行大规模的数据也就会非常顺畅